<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-01-11T05:55:57+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Jayme Hoffman</title><subtitle>Jayme Hoffman's blog</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Best of 2018</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/best-of-2018" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best of 2018" /><published>2018-12-28T15:11:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-28T15:11:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/best-of-2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/best-of-2018">&lt;h2 id=&quot;lessons&quot;&gt;Lessons&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s Next&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you choose what book to read next?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple. Figure out what information you need to get to the next level in life. Prioritize the books you think have this information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find that this simple advice can apply to almost any situation. What should you do next? Prioritize getting the info, skills, people, resources… that help you get to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;failure-is-inevitable&quot;&gt;Failure is Inevitable&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Failure is inevitable. It’s better to fail at what you love than something you compromise to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/title/80209608&quot;&gt;“Jim and Andy”&lt;/a&gt; Netflix documentary, Jim Carrey tells a story about how his Father could’ve done anything in the world but he compromised to taking an accounting job. Years later, he was fired from the accounting job, forcing the Careys into homelessness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“When you compromise and you fail that hurts a lot more than failing at what you love. You can fail at what you don’t love so you might as well do what you love. There’s really no choice to be made.” - Jim Carrey&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;dont-be-a-donkey&quot;&gt;Don’t Be a Donkey&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around Summertime, I found myself pursuing several different directions. I was stressed and felt like I was going nowhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine pointed me to &lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/donkey&quot;&gt;Derek Sivers “Don’t be a donkey”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Buridan’s donkey is standing halfway between a pile of hay and a bucket of water. It keeps looking left and right, trying to decide between hay and water. Unable to decide, it eventually falls over and dies of hunger and thirst.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was an important lesson for me. We can’t do everything all at once. It’s better to focus on one thing at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;determination-trumps-all&quot;&gt;Determination Trumps All&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a good person, eating healthy, abstaining from drugs/alcohol and reading all the self-help books in the world will not make you successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sheer determination to succeed and stick with a thing day in and day out for many years is all that matters. If you have this, you can screw up just about everything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t believe me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thestreet.com/story/14289574/1/warren-buffett-s-junk-food-diet-has-gotten-him-to-87-should-you-follow-it.html&quot;&gt;most successful investor&lt;/a&gt; in the world eats fast food every day.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://fortune.com/2013/01/14/southwests-herb-kelleher-still-crazy-after-all-these-years/&quot;&gt;most successful airline entrepreneur &lt;/a&gt;drinks whiskey and smokes every night.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2016/01/28/upshot/donald-trump-twitter-insults.html&quot;&gt;president of the united states and leader of the free world&lt;/a&gt; is not a nice guy.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;get-lucky-by-moving-forward&quot;&gt;Get Lucky by Moving Forward&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Success has very little to do with where you start in the game. The most important thing is that you just get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of Jeff Bezos success comes from AWS, not Amazon.com. AWS had nothing to do with Jeff’s original idea. He stumbled upon the problem while building Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Li Ka-Shing made most of his success from Hong Kong real estate. He started out manufacturing plastic flowers. He got into real estate development because he needed a new factory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s how success works. You get in the game, execute a strategy and opportunities present themselves as you move forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;books&quot;&gt;Books&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the top 10 books I read in 2018. Thanks to Blinkist for helping me cut through the noise!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2SqIftF&quot;&gt;Man search for meaning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2VjPgOI&quot;&gt;Understanding Media&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2Sp5rZi&quot;&gt;A More Beautiful Question&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2Rt0zoG&quot;&gt;The Obstacle is The Way &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2Rt0LEq&quot;&gt;Deep Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2Rt16qG&quot;&gt;The FOUR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2ViD9By&quot;&gt;Disciplined Entrepreneurship &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2SnmjQd&quot;&gt;Perennial Seller&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2SsJ5X5&quot;&gt;Multipliers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2ViUN8n&quot;&gt;30 Lessons for Living&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;links&quot;&gt;Links&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are my favorites articles, blog posts and videos from 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-superhuman-built-an-engine-to-find-productmarket-fit--first-round-review&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://firstround.com/review/how-superhuman-built-an-engine-to-find-product-market-fit/&quot;&gt;How Superhuman Built an Engine to Find Product/Market Fit | First Round Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Ask your users how they’d feel if they could no longer use your product. The group that answers ‘very disappointed’ will unlock product/market fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;li-ka-shing-biography&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DVJjp_TJd2o&quot;&gt;Li Ka-Shing Biography&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When I was young, I appeared humble but was inwardly very arrogant… So when I went into business, I reminded myself that if I allowed myself to be arrogant, I’d fall one day. And so I named my company Cheung Kong. The Yangtse River doesn’t pick and chose its tributaries. Waters from the small streams and big springs are just pulled over. Otherwise there wouldn’t be any Yangtse, would there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-dozen-things-i-have-learned-from-howard-schultz&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://25iq.com/2014/05/04/a-dozen-things-i-have-learned-from-howard-schultz/&quot;&gt;A Dozen Things I have Learned from Howard Schultz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Success is best when it’s shared.”  “Culture and values trumps strategy.” “Business is a team sport.” “Service is a lost art in America.  It’s not viewed as a professional job to work behind a counter. We don’t believe that. We want to provide our people with dignity and self-esteem, so we offer tangible benefits.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;betting-on-things-that-never-change&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/betting-on-things-that-never-change/&quot;&gt;Betting on Things That Never Change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In the last 100 years we’ve gone from horses to jets and mailing letters to Skype. But every sustainable business is accompanied by one of a handful of timeless strategies… Lower prices, Faster solutions to problems, Greater control over your time, More choices, Added comfort, Entertainment/curiosity, Deeper human interactions, Greater transparency, Less collateral damage, Higher social status, Increased confidence/trust…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;business-lessons-from-mark-leonard-constellation-software&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://25iq.com/2018/04/07/business-lessons-from-mark-leonard-constellation-software/&quot;&gt;Business Lessons from Mark Leonard (Constellation Software)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“CEOs have five essential choices for deploying capital—investing in existing operations, acquiring other businesses, issuing dividends, paying down debt, or repurchasing stock—and three alternatives for raising it—tapping internal cash flow, issuing debt, or raising equity. Think of these options collectively as a tool kit. Over the long term, returns for shareholders will be determined largely by the decisions a CEO makes in choosing which tools to use (and which to avoid) among these various options. Stated simply, two companies with identical operating results and different approaches to allocating capital will derive two very different long-term outcomes for shareholders.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;japanese-style-entrepreneurship-an-interview-with-softbanks-ceo-masayoshi-son&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/1992/01/japanese-style-entrepreneurship-an-interview-with-softbanks-ceo-masayoshi-son&quot;&gt;Japanese-Style Entrepreneurship: An Interview with Softbank’s CEO, Masayoshi Son&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I had all those measurements, about 25 in all, and 40 new ideas. I took a big sheet of paper, and I drew a matrix and put down scores and comments for each. Then I picked the best one, which turned out to be the personal computer software business. That was the start of Softbank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-surprising-power-of-the-long-game&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fs.blog/2018/10/long-game/&quot;&gt;The Surprising Power of The Long Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In everything you do, you’re either playing a short term or long term game. You can’t opt out and you can’t play a long-term game in everything, you need to pick what matters to you. But in everything you do time amplifies the difference between long and short-term games. The question you need to think about is when and where to play a long-term game. A good place to start is with things that compound: knowledge, relationships, and finances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Lessons</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Top 8 Posts on Network Effects</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/network-effects/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Top 8 Posts on Network Effects" /><published>2018-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/network-effects</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/network-effects/">&lt;p&gt;Network Effects are the most powerful force in business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They produced some of the most iconic products and companies ever. Examples: WhatsApp, Airbnb, Google, Amazon, Alibaba, Uber, ebay, Facebook, Opentable, WeChat and Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to venture capital firm, NFX, network effects are responsible for 70% of the value created by tech companies since the Internet became a thing in 1994 🤯&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are my favorite posts on Network Effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;anu-hariharan-on-network-effects&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.ycombinator.com/anu-hariharan-on-network-effects/&quot;&gt;Anu Hariharan on Network Effects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/anuhariharan&quot;&gt;Anu&lt;/a&gt; gives the best explanation of the differences between networks, marketplaces and platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Network&lt;/strong&gt; = group of connected users and you’re sharing information and you’re trying to drive your product. ( fb, WhatsApp, slack )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marketplace&lt;/strong&gt; = two heterogeneous sides. So you have two sites, think of Ebay as a marketplace. You have sellers and buyers. Think of Airbnb, you have hosts and guests. ( eBay, airbnb, instacart )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Platform&lt;/strong&gt; = you have users and developers and a platform. And so think of it where both groups, users and developers, help build the platform, it can be programmatic, customized. But each group reinforces the value of each other. ( apple, microsoft, fb )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;andreesen-horowitz-on-network-effects&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slideshare.net/a16z/network-effects-59206938&quot;&gt;Andreesen Horowitz on Network Effects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anu Hariharan and a16z put together an awesome &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slideshare.net/a16z/network-effects-59206938&quot;&gt;slideshare&lt;/a&gt; deck network effects.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.slidesharecdn.com/networkeffects-v6final-160307161248/95/network-effects-3-638.jpg?cb=1461824597&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;10-factors-to-consider-when-evaluating-digital-marketplaces&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://abovethecrowd.com/2012/11/13/all-markets-are-not-created-equal-10-factors-to-consider-when-evaluating-digital-marketplaces/&quot;&gt;10 Factors To Consider When Evaluating Digital Marketplaces&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bgurley&quot;&gt;Bill Gurley’s&lt;/a&gt; “All Markets Are Not Created Equal” is a legendary post for anyone thinking about building a marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10 factors to consider when evaluating new marketplace opportunity:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New Experience vs. the Status Quo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Economic Advantages vs. the Status Quo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Opportunity for Technology to Add Value&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;High Fragmentation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Friction of Supplier Sign-Up&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Size of the Market Opportunity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Expand the Market&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Frequency&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Payment Flow&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Network Effects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-nfx-of-trulia-building-a-35-billion-marketplace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@nfx/the-nfx-of-trulia-building-a-3-5-billion-marketplace-53e2e738efc8&quot;&gt;The NFX of Trulia: Building a $3.5 Billion Marketplace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/peteflint&quot;&gt;Pete Flint&lt;/a&gt; outlines the building of Trulia’s network effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Our first big challenge, one which every online marketplace must reckon with, was the so-called “chicken-and-egg” problem. How could we attract a consumer audience (homebuyers) without any listings, and how could we attract listings without an audience?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*yM5m2w5RNakRoPwaCeaivg.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-dozen-things-ive-learned-about-multi-sided-markets&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://25iq.com/2016/10/22/a-dozen-things-ive-learned-about-multi-sided-markets-platforms/&quot;&gt;A Dozen Things I’ve Learned about Multi-sided Markets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trent Giffin’s “A Dozen Things I’ve Learned about Multi-sided Markets” is insightful and very easy to digest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recommend reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://25iq.com/featured-individuals/&quot;&gt;everything&lt;/a&gt; Trent writes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multi-sided markets bring together two or more interdependent groups who need each other in some way.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A critical difference between single and multi-sided market is that the sides interact directly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multi-sided markets are not linear.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A multi-sided market is not valuable if the sides can find each other easily.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Demand side economies of scale” result when the value of a product or service changes in a positive way as more people use it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Supply side economies of scale” exist when there are reductions in the average cost per unit associated with increasing the scale of production.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creating a successful multi-sided market requires that the business overcome the “chicken and egg problem.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The chicken and egg problem is best overcome if one side is clearly made the loss leader.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The sides of the market should complement each other – if the sides are complements, it not only reduces the customer acquisition cost (CAC) but assembles sides that want to to enter into exchanges.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Subsidizing the side of the multi-sided market with lower marginal cost/COGS is optimal.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Businesses that are slow to get to critical mass can run out of cash and momentum.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clear profit pools should exist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-network-effects-manual&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nfx.com/post/network-effects-manual&quot;&gt;The Network Effects Manual&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/NFXGuild&quot;&gt;NFX team&lt;/a&gt; take Network Effects to a whole new level with “The Network Effects Manual”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They list out each type of network effect with a diagram, explanation of properties and example companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/fAlINdq.jpg?1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-network-effects-bible&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nfx.com/post/network-effects-bible&quot;&gt;The Network Effects Bible&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/NFXGuild&quot;&gt;NFX team&lt;/a&gt; goes even further with Network Effects by creating “The Network Effects Bible”. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nfx.com/post/network-effects-bible&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slideshare.net/NFXvc/the-network-effects-bible-95560213&quot;&gt;slideshare&lt;/a&gt; are incredibly insightful and a must read for every founder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why Network Effects Are Important&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How Networks Work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Properties of Networks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Building and Maintaining Network Effects&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Related Concepts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.slidesharecdn.com/thenfxbible-finalslideshare1-180501010522/95/the-network-effects-bible-6-1024.jpg?cb=1525385388&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-kardashian-network-effect&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/andrewchen/status/1018933551553810432&quot;&gt;The Kardashian Network Effect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/andrewchen&quot;&gt;Andrew Chen&lt;/a&gt; gives the world a new mental model 😉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Kardashian Network Effect&lt;/strong&gt; - Cross promotion platform built by multiple mutually reinforcing social accounts that cross-promote each other&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Network Effects aren’t just for tech companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/Bb6u0ke.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jaymehoffman/status/1037468438309085185&quot;&gt;Originally tweet stormed at @jaymehoffman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Network Effects are the most powerful force in business.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://image.slidesharecdn.com/networkeffects-v6final-160307161248/95/network-effects-3-638.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Good Markets</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/good-markets/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Good Markets" /><published>2018-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/good-markets</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/good-markets/">&lt;p&gt;According to Marc Andreesen, “product/market fit means being in a Good Market with a product that can satisfy that market.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know the importance of PMF but what defines a Good Market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;good-markets-are-big&quot;&gt;Good markets are big.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arthur Rock, Fairchild Semiconductor: “Give me a giant market — always.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sequoiacap.com/article/elements-of-enduring-companies/&quot;&gt;Sequoia Capital&lt;/a&gt;: A market on the path to a $1B potential allows for error and time for real margins to develop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/nKN-abRJMEw&quot;&gt;Don Valentine, Sequoia Capital&lt;/a&gt;: Target big markets - If you don’t attack a big market, it’s highly unlikely that you’re going to build a big company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;good-markets-are-growing&quot;&gt;Good markets are growing.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/1992/01/japanese-style-entrepreneurship-an-interview-with-softbanks-ceo-masayoshi-son&quot;&gt;Masayoshi Son, SoftBank&lt;/a&gt;: And I wanted to pick a business where the business category itself would be growing for the next 30 to 50 years. I didn’t want to choose a sinking ship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://web.archive.org/web/20070701074943/http://blog.pmarca.com/2007/06/the-pmarca-gu-2.html&quot;&gt;Marc Andreesen&lt;/a&gt;: And the market will range from booming to comatose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@nico_bst/how-to-identify-a-good-market-to-launch-a-successful-startup-d82214f07551&quot;&gt;Nicolas Bustamante&lt;/a&gt;: The market is growing and so the problem increases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;good-markets-are-rich-and-hungry&quot;&gt;Good markets are rich and hungry.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Four-Steps-Epiphany-Steve-Blank/dp/0989200507&quot;&gt;Steve Blank&lt;/a&gt;: Customer Validation proves that you have found a set of customers and a market who react positively to the product: By relieving those customers of some of their money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sequoiacap.com/article/elements-of-enduring-companies/&quot;&gt;Sequoia Capital&lt;/a&gt;: Target customers who will move fast and pay a premium for a unique offering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://a16z.com/2017/02/18/12-things-about-product-market-fit/&quot;&gt;Andy Rachleff&lt;/a&gt;: “If you address a market that really wants your product — if the dogs are eating the dog food — then you can screw up almost everything in the company and you will succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;good-markets-have-existing-solutions&quot;&gt;Good markets have existing solutions.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/nKN-abRJMEw&quot;&gt;Don Valentine, Sequoia Capital&lt;/a&gt;: A lot of successful products are knock offs of products with huge market shares held by companies like Sony (iPod vs. walkman )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://a16z.com/2017/02/18/12-things-about-product-market-fit/&quot;&gt;Andy Rachleff, CEO Wealthfront&lt;/a&gt;: “First to market seldom matters. Rather, first to product/market fit is almost always the long-term winner.” “Time after time, the winner is the first company to deliver the food the dogs want to eat.” “Once a company has achieved product market fit, it is extremely difficult to dislodge it, even with a better or less expensive product.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;good-markets-fit-their-founders&quot;&gt;Good markets fit their founders.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paulgraham.com/organic.html&quot;&gt;Paul Graham, YC&lt;/a&gt;: The best way to come up with startup ideas is to ask yourself the question: what do you wish someone would make for you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/1992/01/japanese-style-entrepreneurship-an-interview-with-softbanks-ceo-masayoshi-son&quot;&gt;Masayoshi Son, SoftBank&lt;/a&gt;: One success measure was that I should fall in love with a particular business for the next 50 years at least. Very often, people get excited for the first few years, and then, after they see the reality, they get tired of the business. I wanted to choose one that I would feel more and more excited about as the years passed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdixon.org/2011/06/20/foundermarket-fit/&quot;&gt;Chris Dixon, a16z Crypto&lt;/a&gt;:  You should fit your market not only because you understand it, but because you love it — and will continue to love it as your product and market change over time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">According to Marc Andreesen, “product/market fit means being in a Good Market with a product that can satisfy that market.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Two Paths to Product Market Fit</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/two-paths-to-product-market-fit/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Two Paths to Product Market Fit" /><published>2018-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/two-paths-to-product-market-fit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/two-paths-to-product-market-fit/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-product-market-fit&quot;&gt;What is product market fit?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Product/market fit means being in a good market with a product that can satisfy that market.” -pmarca&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“If you address a market that really wants your product — if the dogs are eating the dog food — then you can screw up almost everything in the company and you will succeed. Conversely, if you’re really good at execution but the dogs don’t want to eat the dog food, you have no chance of winning.” Andy Rachleff&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;there-are-two-paths-to-product-market-fit&quot;&gt;There are two paths to product market fit.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Start with a market. Find a product for the market.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Start with a product. Find a market for the product.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;market-first&quot;&gt;Market First&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But too often the focus is on latter part of the sentence (a product that can satisfy the market) and not the former (in a good market). Andreessen emphasizes that market matters most: “You can obviously screw up a great market — and that has been done, and not infrequently — but assuming the team is baseline competent and the product is fundamentally acceptable, a great market will tend to equal success and a poor market will tend to equal failure.” That’s why time spent building a business around the product alone is pointless: “Best case, it’s going to be a zombie. … in a terrible market, you can have the best product in the world and an absolutely killer team, and it doesn’t matter – you’re going to fail. &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16z.com/2017/02/18/12-things-about-product-market-fit/&quot;&gt;(a16z)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Marc Andreessen writes: “In a great market — a market with lots of real potential customers — the market pulls product out of the startup.” &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16z.com/2017/02/18/12-things-about-product-market-fit/&quot;&gt;(a16z)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Founders have to choose a market long before they have any idea whether they will reach product/market fit.” Chris Dixon &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdixon.org/2011/06/20/foundermarket-fit/&quot;&gt;(cdixon)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;product-first&quot;&gt;Product First&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Product 1st, Market 2nd: Most successful new markets begin with a market-sensitive technologist recognizing an inflection point that enables a new kind of product. The next question becomes: “who wants to buy my product?” Start with the product and search for the market as opposed to vice versa. Evaluating a market trying to find holes and developing solutions for those problems will lead to mundane outcomes. &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/parsa-vc/7-lessons-from-andy-rachleff-on-product-market-fit-9fc5eceb4432&quot;&gt;(Medium)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Even though serendipity plays a role here, there is a process — which is why Rachleff later created and teaches a course at Stanford, Aligning Startups with their Markets. Steve Blank also developed a customer development process based on the idea that startups should apply the scientific method just like scientists do: start with a hypothesis, test it, prove it, move on or further iterate on the hypothesis. Similarly, Rachleff observes that “First you need to define and test your value hypothesis. And then only once proven do you move on to your growth hypothesis. The value hypothesis defines the what, the who, and the how. What are you going to build, who is desperate for it, and what is the business model you are going to use to deliver it?” Startups should therefore start with the product and try to find the market, as opposed to starting with the market to find the product. It’s important to emphasize here that the iteration is more about the market and the business model than the product itself. &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16z.com/2017/02/18/12-things-about-product-market-fit/&quot;&gt;a16z&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">What is product market fit?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sunbird Approach - Transporting Proven Models</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/sunbird-approach/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sunbird Approach - Transporting Proven Models" /><published>2018-08-04T16:54:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-04T16:54:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/sunbird-approach</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/sunbird-approach/">&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jhoff/status/1024103136536014853&quot;&gt;recently discovered&lt;/a&gt; that Netflix was NOT founded because Blockbuster charged Reed Hastings with a $40 late fee for “Apollo 13”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, the founders wanted to create “The Amazon of X,” and settled on DVDs…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not a bad thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Creators-Code-Essential-Extraordinary-Entrepreneurs/dp/1451666071&quot;&gt;Creators’s Code&lt;/a&gt; classifies the Netflix founding story as a Sunbird Approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Sunbirds transport solutions that work in one area and apply them to another, often with a twist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Sunbirds take something that already exists and transport the model to create something new. they relocate and reshape existing concepts across geographies and industries, and bring old ideas up to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;They examine how and why it worked initially, and what similarities or differences will make it work again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a list of proven models (Amazon of X) that can be transported to other markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;proven-models-to-transport&quot;&gt;Proven models to transport:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Glossier of X = &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inc.com/emily-canal/glossier-2017-company-of-the-year-nominee.html&quot;&gt;Content + Commerce&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;playbook&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;grow content &amp;amp; community around an area of life&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;sell stuff and/or services to community&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;examples&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Goop&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;DrAxe&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Yeti of X = &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/online-direct-to-consumer-brands-with-retail-stores-locations-2018-2&quot;&gt;Direct to Consumer Brand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;playbook&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;upgrade stale product category&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;create a brand&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;examples&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Warby Parker&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Harrys&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Away&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Outdoor Voices&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Houzz of X = &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nfx.com/post/10-years-about-market-networks&quot;&gt;Market Network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;playbook&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;create a network&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;add marketplace/saas functionality&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;examples&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Honeybook&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;AngelList&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Salesforce of X = &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davidcummings/status/1019549219630305285&quot;&gt;Saas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;playbook&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;create software in path of revenue or mission critical workflow&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;sell, sell, sell&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;examples&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Hubspot&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Pardot&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Segment&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Netflix of X = &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inc.com/magazine/201605/kris-frieswick/peloton-studio-cycling-home-fitness.html&quot;&gt;Subscription content&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;playbook&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;create/aggregate content&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;grow subscribers&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;examples&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Headspace&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Peloton&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Blinkist&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Airbnb of X = &lt;a href=&quot;https://andrewchen.co/marketplace-startups-best-essays/&quot;&gt;Marketplace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;playbook&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;aggregate suppliers&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;grow GMV&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;examples&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Breather&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;OYO&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;CarMax of X = Reselling&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;playbook&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;buy asset at a discount&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;sell asset for a profit&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;examples&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Opendoor&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;E-cycle&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Red Ventures of X = Lead generation&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;playbook&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;acquire leads (with content or ads)&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;sell leads&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;examples&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Technology Advice&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Nerdwallet&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Tencent of X = &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@efeng/who-has-the-best-business-model-and-its-not-google-or-facebook-ca36f967bbd1&quot;&gt;Shared Value Transactions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;playbook&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;charge your very best users more to unlock more of the product&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;a small percentage of your user base will drive 1,000 times more value to the business than the average user.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;As Bezos has &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2016/05/31/jeff-bezos-on-space-free-speech-and-creating-shows-to-sell-more-shoes/&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;: “&lt;em&gt;When we win a Golden Globe, it helps us sell more shoes&lt;/em&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;examples&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;QVC&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;free mobile games&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I recently discovered that Netflix was NOT founded because Blockbuster charged Reed Hastings with a $40 late fee for “Apollo 13”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Helpful Links</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/links" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Helpful Links" /><published>2017-06-30T17:50:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-30T17:50:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/links</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/links">&lt;p&gt;Here’s a list of helpful articles, essays and videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;customer-obsession&quot;&gt;Customer Obsession&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Do whatever is best for your users. You can hold onto that like a rope in a hurricane and it will save you if anything can. You just pull on that rope and it will guide you through everything you have to do. - Paul Graham&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=q7K0vRUKXKc&quot;&gt;Paul Graham Speaks to Startup School ( video )&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-hxX_Q5CnaA&quot;&gt;Jeff Bezos announces Zappos acquisition ( video )&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1018724/000119312516530910/d168744dex991.htm&quot;&gt;Amazon 1998 shareholder letter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=2&amp;amp;v=pgKcwEkip9I&quot;&gt;SoftBank Commercial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-ideas&quot;&gt;Getting Ideas&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Given one hour to save the world, I would spend 55 minutes defining the problem and 5 minutes finding the solution. - Albert Einstein*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://awealthofcommonsense.com/2017/12/best-idea-wins/&quot;&gt;The Best Idea Wins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2009/12/fear-of-bad-ideas.html&quot;&gt;Fear of bad ideas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/multiply&quot;&gt;Ideas are just a multiplier of execution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdixon.org/2010/01/03/the-next-big-thing-will-start-out-looking-like-a-toy/&quot;&gt;The next big thing will start out looking like a toy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://paulgraham.com/start.html&quot;&gt;How to Start a Startup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;testing--building-products&quot;&gt;Testing &amp;amp; Building Products&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And you can always feel product/market fit when it’s happening. The customers are buying the product just as fast as you can make it – or usage is growing just as fast as you can add more servers. Money from customers is piling up in your company checking account. You’re hiring sales and customer support staff as fast as you can. Reporters are calling because they’ve heard about your hot new thing and they want to talk to you about it. You start getting entrepreneur of the year awards from Harvard Business School. Investment bankers are staking out your house. You could eat free for a year at Buck’s. - Pmarca&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pmarchive.com/guide_to_startups_part4.html&quot;&gt;The only thing that matters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://a16z.com/2017/02/18/12-things-about-product-market-fit/&quot;&gt;12 Things about PMF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.ycombinator.com/minimum-viable-product-process/&quot;&gt;A Minimum Viable Product Is Not a Product, It’s a Process&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hackernoon.com/the-mvp-is-dead-long-live-the-rat-233d5d16ab02&quot;&gt;The MVP is dead. Long live the RAT.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_6pl5GG8RQ4&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;amp;t=37m32s&quot;&gt;How to Find Product Market Fit - CS183F ( video )&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://paulbuchheit.blogspot.com/2010/02/if-your-product-is-great-it-doesnt-need.html?m=1&quot;&gt;If your product is Great, it doesn’t need to be Good.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://firstround.com/review/90-of-feedback-is-crap-how-to-find-the-next-big-startup-idea/&quot;&gt;90% of Feedback is Crap: How to Find the Next Big Startup Idea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/on-startups/blog-first-startups-968ebef44a56&quot;&gt;Blog first startups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;platforms-marketplaces--networks&quot;&gt;Platforms, Marketplaces &amp;amp; Networks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vLsnYCPdNtc&quot;&gt;Anu Hariharan on Network Effects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://abovethecrowd.com/2012/11/13/all-markets-are-not-created-equal-10-factors-to-consider-when-evaluating-digital-marketplaces/&quot;&gt;10 Factors To Consider When Evaluating Digital Marketplaces&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://versionone.vc/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Marketplace-Handbook-11-08-2015.pdf#page=48&quot;&gt;A guide to marketplaces&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2016/04/pipelines-platforms-and-the-new-rules-of-strategy&quot;&gt;Pipelines, Platforms, and the New Rules of Strategy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;growing-products&quot;&gt;Growing Products&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Dominate a small yet extensible market first: Facebook - Harvard, Amazon - books, Netflix - DVD mailers, Uber - town cars in SF - &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davidsacks/status/689848729839411201&quot;&gt;David Sacks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://kk.org/thetechnium/1000-true-fans/&quot;&gt;1,000 True Fans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://25iq.com/2017/02/10/a-dozen-lessons-on-growth/&quot;&gt;A Dozen Lessons on Growth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paulgraham.com/growth.html&quot;&gt;Startup = Growth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n_yHZ_vKjno&quot;&gt;Alex Schultz - Growth ( video )&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;brand&quot;&gt;Brand&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brands always mean something. If you don’t define what the brands means, your competitors will - Richard Branson&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hvaOu5kCFgU&quot;&gt;$100,000 of Brand Strategy Advice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trackchanges.postlight.com/against-storytelling-7e53b6d7a0d8&quot;&gt;Against Storytelling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://library.gv.com/the-three-hour-brand-sprint-3ccabf4b768a&quot;&gt;Google Ventures Brand Sprint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slideshare.net/kirkphillips/the-9-crit/10-What_you_make_people_feel&quot;&gt;What you make people feel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;team--culture&quot;&gt;Team / Culture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;People don’t buy what you do. They buy why you do it. - Simon Sinek&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://firstround.com/review/radical-candor-the-surprising-secret-to-being-a-good-boss/&quot;&gt;Radical Candor — The Surprising Secret to Being a Good Boss&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.idonethis.com/manager-focus-peter-thiel-paypal/&quot;&gt;Peter Thiel’s Philosophy of Extreme Manager Focus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://josephwalla.com/your-job-as-a-founder-is-to-create-believers&quot;&gt;Your Job As a Founder Is to Create Believers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://airows.com/creative/a-look-inside-the-beautiful-handbook-facebook-gives-all-new-employees&quot;&gt;Facebook was not originally created to be a company&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://culturecodes.co/&quot;&gt;A collection of culture decks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fundraising&quot;&gt;Fundraising&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The reality is that visionaries like Steve Jobs haven’t been successful because they thought of something amazing and original out of thin air. Rather, they were gifted at constantly persuading many people to follow them on their journey to something amazing and original. - Tyler Odean&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://firstround.com/review/master-the-art-of-influence-persuasion-as-a-skill-and-habit/&quot;&gt;Master the Art of Influence — Persuasion as a Skill and Habit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hackernoon.com/how-we-raised-a-7-million-series-a-from-foundry-group-our-top-choice-vc-8b630d2a4cef&quot;&gt;How We Raised a $7 Million Series A from our Top Choice VC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://reactionwheel.net/2017/10/ruling-out-rather-than-ruling-in.html&quot;&gt;Ruling out rather than ruling in&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.saastr.com/what-are-some-rookie-mistakes-founders-make-during-vc-meetings/&quot;&gt;What are some rookie mistakes founders make during VC meetings?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://venturehacks.wpengine.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/12/Pitching-Hacks.pdf&quot;&gt;Venturehacks - Pitching Hacks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.ycombinator.com/guide-to-demo-day-pitches/&quot;&gt;Guide to demo day presentations - YC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/startup-grind/55-things-learned-as-a-19-year-old-vc-6c54af2f0f89#.2w9617owj&quot;&gt;55 things learned as a 19 year old VC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.eladgil.com/2017/02/building-vc-relationships.html&quot;&gt;Building VC Relationships&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aaronkharris.com/advice-on-pitching&quot;&gt;Advice on pitching&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tomtunguz.com/inevitability/?utm_content=buffer1e3a8&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;amp;utm_campaign=buffer&quot;&gt;The Secret Ingredient To The Best Startup Fundraising Pitches&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.ycombinator.com/intro-to-the-yc-seed-deck/&quot;&gt;The YC Seed Deck Template&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fear-of-failure&quot;&gt;Fear of Failure&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The essential part of creativity is not being afraid to fail. - Edwin Land&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uky.edu/\~eushe2/Pajares/OnFailingG.html&quot;&gt;But They Did Not Give Up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZXsQAXx_ao0&quot;&gt;Shia LaBeouf “Just Do It”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Here’s a list of helpful articles, essays and videos.</summary></entry></feed>